What we see
and what we seem
are but a dream .
A dream within a dream .
( SLOW , ETHEREAL ROMANIAN PANPIPE MUSIC )
" Meet me , love , when day is ending . "
" I love thee for thy highborn grace ,
" Thy deep and lustrous eye ,
" For the sweet meaning of thy brow ,
" and for thy bearing so high . "
Six
and seven
and eight
and nine
and ten
and eleven .
" I love thee
" Not because thou art fair ,
" Softer than down , smoother than air ,
" Nor for the cupids that do lie
" In either corner of thine eye .
" Wouldst thou then know what it might be ?
" Tis I love thee ' cause thou lov 'st me . "
Tighter .
Is that tight enough ?
Not too tight .
( PANPIPE MUSIC CONTINUES )
( SPEECH INAUDIBLE )
( MUSIC FADES )
♪ See the little horse ,
♪ My little horse ,
♪ Trotting down the paddock On his fine white feet
♪ Black horse , white horse ,
♪ Brown horse , grey
♪ Trotting down the paddock On a bright , sunny day . ♪
Someday , Sara , you shall have to come home with me to the station .
To Queensland .
And meet my sweet , funny family for yourself .
Would you like that ?
( MOUTHS WORDS )
You must learn to love ...
someone else apart from me , Sara .
I won 't be here much longer .
What do you think ?
Miranda , somebody had the nerve to send Miss McCraw a card on squared paper
covered with tiny sums .
( CHATTING )
Happy Valentine 's , Mam 'selle .
( SPEECH INAUDIBLE )
( GIRLS STILL CHATTING )
Girls ! Girls !
Unless you all deport yourselves with rather more grace
and considerably less noise ,
Mrs Appleyard will see to it that none of you go to Hanging Rock today .
Bonjour , Miss Lumley .
Good morning , Mademoiselle de Poitiers .
I believe Mrs Appleyard has decided you 're not to go on the picnic , Sara .
That makes two of us .
Off you go !
To St Valentine !
- ( CHEERING ) - Shh !
( QUIET CHATTER )
Miranda ?
Settle down , please .
Backs straight .
Into position . Hurry up !
♪ Frère Jacques , Frère Jacques , Dormez vous ... ♪
( CLOCK TICKING ) ( SINGING CAN BE HEARD )
Going to have to do that for us today .
Tais-toi , Irma . Miss McCraw vient d 'arriver .
- ( WHISPERS ) She wants algebra today . - Today ?
( WHISPERING )
( BELL RINGS )
( CHATTING AND LAUGHING )
- Good morning , girls . - Good morning , Mrs Appleyard .
Well , young ladies ,
we are indeed fortunate in the weather for our picnic to Hanging Rock .
I have instructed Mademoiselle
that as the day is likely to be warm , you may remove your gloves
once the drag has passed through Woodend .
You will partake of luncheon at the picnic grounds near the rock .
Once again let me remind you that the rock itself is extremely dangerous
and you are therefore forbidden any tomboy foolishness in the matter of exploration ,
even on the lower slopes .
I also wish to remind you the vicinity is renowned for its venomous snakes
and poisonous ants of various species .
It is , however , a geological marvel ,
on which you will be required to write a brief essay on Monday morning .
That is all .
Have a pleasant day , and try to behave yourselves
in a manner to bring credit to the college .
Mr Hussey ?
Mr Hussey !
I shall expect you back , Miss McCraw and Mademoiselle , at about eight
for a light supper .
Come , girls .
( ♪ BACH : " Prelude No 1 in C " )
This we do for pleasure
so that we may shortly be at the mercy of venomous snakes and poisonous ants .
How foolish can human creatures be ?
( MUSIC CONTINUES )
( CHILDREN SHOUTING )
( WHISTLING )
- There she is , ladies . Hangin ' Rock . - ( GIRLS GASP )
( MUSIC STOPS )
The mountain comes to Mohammed . A hanging rock comes to Mr Hussey .
More than 500 feet high she is . Volcanic , of course . Thousands of years old .
A million years old , Mr Hussey , or thereabouts .
Yes , well , of course that 'd be right .
Thousands , millions .
Devil of a long time , anyway , IN a manner of speakin ' .
Only a million years ago . Quite a recent eruption , really .
The rocks all around Mount Macedon itself must be all of 350 million years old .
Siliceous lava
forced up from deep down below .
Soda trachytes extruded in a highly viscous state ,
building the steep-sided mametons we see in Hanging Rock .
And quite young , geologically speaking .
Barely a million years .
Waiting a million years ...
just for us .
( BIRDS TWEETING )
( FLY BUZZING )
More cake , Michael ?
No , thank you , Aunt . I 'm ...
I think I 'll just , um , stretch my legs a bit .
Oh , don 't go too far .
And be careful - there could be snakes .
( BUZZING )
( UNEVEN BUZZING )
- How 's it goin ' ? - All right .
They finished eating , have they ?
Pardon ?
The colonel and the missus .
- They finished eating , have they ? - Oh , yes , they have .
Expect me up there in a minute , I suppose . Clear away .
- Can 't be more 'n midday . - No .
( BIRDSONG AND INSECTS BUZZING )
I thought it was a little early for lunch myself .
Yeah .
Drink ?
Thanks .
You know , they always allow an hour longer than it takes to get ' ere ,
and then they got ' ere straight away .
Thanks .
Ta !
Not that they got anything else to do .
I mean , they never go for a walk or nothin ' .
MR HUSSEY : Get on ! Come on !
( SHOUTS OF EXCITEMENT )
- ( BIRDS TWEETING ) - ( HORSES WHINNY )
( LOW , HAUNTING PANPIPE MUSIC )
- MIRANDA : To St Valentine ! - ALL : To St Valentine !
( CHEERING )
( MUSIC STOPS )
( LOW RUMBLING )
( GIRLS CHATTING )
( DOOR CLOSES )
I hope you have learned your poetry , Sara .
Sit up straight , child .
Hold your shoulders back . You 're getting a dreadful stoop .
Well , have you got your lines by heart ?
Well , have you ?
I can 't . It doesn 't make sense .
Sense ? You little ignoramus !
Evidently you don 't know
that Mrs Felicia Heymans is considered one of the finest of our English poets .
I know another piece of poetry by heart .
It has ever so many verses , much more than ' The Wreck of the Hesperus ' .
Would that do ?
What is the name of this poem ?
' An Ode to St Valentine ' .
I 'm not acquainted with it . Where did you find it ?
I didn 't find it . I wrote it .
You wrote it ?
" Love abounds , love surrounds ... "
Oh , no thank you , Sara . Strange as it may seem , I still prefer Mrs Heymans .
Give me your book and proceed to recite to me as far as you have gone .
Your book , please , Sara .
Thank you .
Go on .
I can 't .
Not one line ?
I shall leave you now , Sara .
I expect you to be word perfect when I send Miss Lumley in in half an hour .
Otherwise , I 'm afraid I shall have to send you to bed
instead of letting you stay up until the others return from the picnic .
( WHISPERS ) Bertie ! Bertie !
Jesus , where are you ?
Oh , Miranda !
( INSECTS CHIRPING )
I like this one .
" Shall I compare thee to a summer 's day ?
" Thou art more lovely and more temperate .
" Rough winds do shake the darling buds of May ,
" And summer 's lease hath all too short a date ... "
( CONTINUES READING SONNET )
( MAM 'SELLE RECITING IN FRENCH )
MR HUSSEY : That 's funny !
Blowed if me watch hasn 't stopped .
Dead on 12.00 .
That 's real funny .
( FINISHES RECITING )
C 'est très jolie , n 'est-ce pas " ?
You wouldn 't have the time , I suppose , miss ?
Ah , Miranda , your pretty little diamond watch .
Don 't wear it any more .
Can 't stand the ticking above my heart .
Ah !
If it were mine ...
I 'd wear it always , even in the bath .
Would you , Mr Hussey ?
Stopped at twelve .
Never stopped before .
Must be something magnetic .
Well after two , I 'd say .
We 'd better be careful .
I promised Mrs Appleyard I 'd have you lot back at the college by eight .
IRMA : You know what , Mam 'selle ?
- I 'd like to go to Paris , with you . - No , no , no .
Except for those people down there ...
we might be the only living creatures in the whole world .
( ETHEREAL PANPIPE MUSIC )
- Excuse me , Mam 'selle . - Yes , Marion ?
I should like to make a few measurements at the base of the rock if we have time .
With Miranda and Irma .
IRMA : Oh , please , Mam 'selle .
We 'll be back long before tea .
Et bien . Allez !
May I come too , please ?
MARION : So long as you don 't complain .
I won 't . I promise .
And don 't worry about us , Mam 'selle .
We shall only be gone a little while .
( MUSIC CONTINUES )
Ah !
Now I know .
What do you know ?
I know that Miranda is a Botticelli angel .
( GIRLS LAUGHING )
EDITH : Wait !
I 'd better take a flying leap .
- MIRANDA : Can you manage it , Edith ? - I don 't know .
I don 't want to get my feet wet .
( MUSIC FADES )
Oh !
( HE WHISTLES )
Thought the little fat one was gonna take a bath .
Some of them are real lookers .
Have a look at the shape of the dark one with the curls .
Built like an hourglass .
And ' ave a go at the last one ! The blonde !
Oh , she 'd have a decent pair a " legs .
All the way up to her bum .
I 'd rather you didn 't say crude things like that , Albert .
I say the crude things . You just think ' em .
EDITH : Miranda !
Take my word for it .
The Sheilas are all alike when it comes to fellas .
Doesn 't matter if it 's a bloody college you come from
or the Ballarat Orphanage where me and me kid sister was dragged up .
Didn 't know you were an orphan .
Jeez ! I haven 't thought of that bloody dump in donkeys ' years .
( PANPIPE MUSIC )
( ECHO ) Miranda !
I think I 'll just , er ... stretch my legs a bit before we go .
( MUSIC FADES )
( WATER RUSHING )
( LYRICAL MUSIC WITH PIANO MELODY )
Look !
Not down at the ground , Edith . Way up there in the sky .
( MUSIC BUILDS WITH CHORAL ELEMENT )
( MUSIC CONTINUES )
( MUSIC FADES )
Why can 't we just sit on this log and look at the ugly old rock from here ?
It 's nasty here !
I never thought it would be so nasty , or I wouldn 't have come !
( EERIE DRONING )
( TAPPING )
( WIND RUMBLES )
We can 't go much further .
We promised Mam 'selle
we wouldn 't be long away .
( PANPIPE THEME )
If only we could stay out all night ... and watch the moon rise .
EDITH : Blanche said Sara writes poetry in the dunny !
She found one there on the floor all about Miranda .
She 's an orphan .
IRMA : Sara reminds me of a little deer Papa brought home once .
I looked after it
but it died .
Mama always said it was doomed .
Doomed ? What 's that mean , Irma ?
Doomed to die , of course .
" The boy stood on the burning deck , whence all but he had fled , tra la ... "
I forget the rest .
I think I must be doomed .
I don 't feel at all well .
I do wish you 'd stop talking for once .
Poor Edith . We 'll go back soon .
( PANPIPE MUSIC CONTINUES )
( MUSIC CONTINUES )
Irma ! Look at them !
Where in the world are they going ?
Without their shoes !
Irma , wait ! Wait for me ! Please wait !
Wait , Irma , wait !
( MUSIC FADES )
Whatever can those people be doing down there ?
Like a lot of ants .
A surprising number of human beings are without purpose .
Although it is probable they 're performing some function unknown to themselves .
MIRANDA : Everything begins and ends
at exactly the right time and place .
Look !
( LOW DRONE AND HIGH-PITCHED EERIE SHRIEK )
( LOW RUMBLING )
( LOW RUMBLING AND INSECTS CHIRPING )
( LOW RUMBLING CONTINUES )
( BIRDS CAWING )
EDITH : Oh , Miranda , I feel awful ... really awful .
Miranda , I feel perfectly awful .
When are we going home ?
( RUMBLING CONTINUES )
Miranda ?
Miranda !
( CRIES ) Miranda !
( SHOUTS ) Miranda , don 't go up there ! Come back !
( SCREAMS LOUDLY )
( CONTINUES SCREAMING )
( EERIE ECHOES )
( CLOCK TICKING )
( BELL RINGS )
I 've gotta go . That 's Mrs Appleyard .
Let someone else go .
They won 't . No . I 'm on .
Right . What time is it ?
( SHE GIGGLES )
It 's time to go !
What 've you got to do ? I 've got to go .
Mrs Appleyard 'll skin me .
We got plenty of time .
( BELL RINGS )
You 'd better go .
( CLOCK TICKS )
( INSECTS CHIRPING )
( WHISPERS ) Why are they so late ?
( HORSES ' HOOVES )
( BELL RINGS )
God be praised !
Mademoiselle , why are you so late ?
Madame ...
something terrible has happened .
What ?
What do you mean ?
I can 't ...
And where in heaven 's name is Miss McCraw ?
We left her behind at the rock .
You left her behind ?
( GIRLS CRYING )
Has everyone taken leave of their senses ?
Miss Lumley , get these girls to bed immediately .
And Cook , Cook ! Hot soup , please , for all of them .
Mrs Appleyard ...
I must speak to you alone .
Very well .
Straight up the stairs , girls . Come along , quickly as you can .
Cook , I asked you for hot soup !
Well , ma 'am ... ma 'am ,
the strength of it is this .
Three of your young ladies
and , er ... Miss McCraw
are m-missing ...
on the rock .
What happened ?
Well , now , Mrs Appleyard ...
That 's just the trouble .
Nobody knows what happened .
How soon after the girls did Miss McCraw leave ?
Don 't know . No one knows .
No one saw her leave . We were asleep .
And the little one ?
Edith Horton .
Like I told ya
she come tearin ' out of the bushes , dress all torn
screamin ' fit to ...
Well , after we 'd shushed her screamin ' , all we could get out of her
was that she 'd left the other three somewhere up on the rock .
That 's about all I can tell ya .
( INSECTS BUZZING )
Miranda !
( DRUMMING )
Marion !
Irma !
( CALLING AND DRUMMING )
( DRUMMING STOPS )
Go on , get out of it .
Ah , stop it !
Come on .
Miranda !
( FLY BUZZING )
Try to remember , Edith
what it was that frightened you on the rock .
Think carefully , darling . Carefully !
Did you speak to anyone ?
There must have been something .
Was there a man ?
I do hope you don 't blame yourself .
After all , no one can be held responsible for the pranks of destiny .
And besides , it may well turn out to be a storm in a teacup .
Her legs were quite severely scratched .
From running through the brambles , I should imagine .
Nothing else ?
Nothing I could detect .
She hadn 't been
molested ?
No , no , nothing like that .
I have examined her .
She is quite intact .
Since you won 't tell me all the details , how can I give you an opinion , Lionel ?
There are no details .
People just don 't disappear , my dear .
Not without good reason .
There 's talk , is there ?
Not just gossip .
People have ...
- ... theories . - Goon .
Well , it couldn 't be local .
What couldn 't ?
No one around here would do a thing like that .
I 've just told you , Sergeant .
I simply noticed these three young ladies crossing the creek .
What did they look like ?
Hm ?
The girls . Describe them to me .
Um ...
The first one was tall and dark .
Um ... Then there was the little dumpy one .
Um ... then a girl with glasses ...
and ...
the last one was ... slim and fair .
That 's four .
Pardon ?
A few minutes ago you said there was only three of them .
Oh , oh , yes .
That 's because the ... dumpy one was back a little .
Then they ... er ... moved off into the trees
and that 's the last we saw of them .
Did they know you were watching them ?
I couldn 't be sure .
They made no sign .
But Albert did whistle at them .
Which way now , Edith ?
I don 't know . It all looks the same .
I was frightened .
I don 't know why .
Think , chérie . You have been doing very well so far .
I was tired .
I wanted to go back .
Perhaps we could go a little higher .
I was tired .
I sat down on a log .
Which log , Edith ? This one ?
Look around you , darling .
Maybe you can see it now .
Is that the one ? You went that way ?
I don 't know . I was tired . I 'm tired now .
There is one thing I remember .
What do you remember , Edith ? Tell us .
It was when I was coming down , when I was running .
It was a cloud .
What sort of a cloud ?
It was red .
I remember it clearly . It was just after I passed Miss McCraw .
Who did you say you saw ?
Miss McCraw . She was going up the hill as I was going down .
Did she stop ?
Did you speak ?
No . She was too far away .
She was about as far away as those dead trees are over there .
( GIGGLING )
She was funny .
Funny ?
How ?
I 'd rather not say .
You must , Edith . It could be very important .
It 's rude .
Les pantalons .
She had no skirt . Just les pantalons .
Drawers ?
You mean she was just wearing drawers ?
One last go .
For the bloodhound .
( ♪ BEETHOVEN : " Adagio " from 5th Piano Concerto )
Miranda .
( DOG BARKS )
Hello !
( MUSIC ENDS )
Why didn 't you tell us you followed the four girls ?
Because
I didn 't exactly follow them .
I just jumped across the creek and walked towards the rock for a little way .
I was curious .
In England young ladies like that wouldn 't be allowed to go walking in the forest .
Not alone , anyway .
But they 'd gone by the time I 'd come out of the trees
so I turned back .
As the girls were jumping the creek
what were you thinking of ?
Uh ...
Hm ?
( STRING QUARTET PLAYS MOZART : " Romance : Andante " from " Eine Kleine Nachtmusik " )
Ah , Michael !
( QUIET CHATTER )
Oh , Michael ! I ...
The old man hired me to look after the horses .
I 'm buggered if I 'm gonna be a lackey at a bloody garden party .
That 's what I bloody well told I 'm .
More or less .
Had the bloodhound out the other day .
I wake up every night in a cold sweat .
Just wondering if they 're still alive .
Yeah , well , the way I look at it is this .
If the bloody cop and the bloody abo tracker and the bloody dog can 't find ' em ,
well , no one bloody can .
( QUARTET PLAYS TCHAIKOVSKY : " Andante Cantabile " String Quartet No1 , Op 11 )
People have been bushed before today ,
and as far as I 'm concerned , that 's the stone end of it .
Well , it 's not the end of it as far as I 'm concerned .
They may be out there
dying of thirst on
on that infernal rock and
you and I are sitting here drinking cold bloody beer .
That 's where you and me 's different .
If you want my advice , the sooner you forget the whole thing , the better .
Well , I can 't forget it , and I never will .
- ( QUARTET PLAYS " God Save the Queen " ) - ( ALBERT LAUGHS )
I 'm not great shakes on music , but I reckon the governor must be leavin ' , eh ?
Your auntie 'll give you hell if you 're not on show .
Albert ...
( QUARTET FINISHES )
I want to go back to the rock .
To look for them .
Will you come with me ?
Beautiful birds , them swans .
A week in the bush .
They 'd be dead by now .
Then I 'll go alone .
( LYRICAL MUSIC WITH PIANO MELODY )
( MUSIC BUILDS )
Coo-ee !
Hello ?
( MUSIC FADES )
Coo-ee !
Mike !
Michael !
We 'll have to be goin ' soon .
Dark before we get back .
I 'm staying here .
You 're what ?
- Here ? On the rock ? - Yes .
What the hell for ?
- You 're mad . - Yes , perhaps I am .
But I 'm still staying , because somebody has to .
- Just because you lot are Australians ... - You 're a funny bugger .
What the hell am I gonna tell ' em when I get back there without ya ?
You can tell ' em what you like .
Hm ? What ? Woodend ?
The Victoria , sir . The little pub near the corner .
Mr Michael 's pretty knocked out , sir .
He 's sleepin ' there .
The pub .
Yeah . Yeah .
I 'm dashed if I know how his aunt 'll take it .
Yeah .
All right . Carry on , Crundall .
Thank you , sir .
Yeah ...
( PANPIPE THEME )
( WATER RUSHING )
MICHAEL . : I think I 'll just ... stretch my legs a bit before we go .
( MUSIC FADES )
( BIRDSONG )
( LOW , RHYTHMIC BOOMING )
( HAUNTING , ATONAL MUSIC )
MISS McCRAW : Stopped at 12 . Never stopped before .
MIRANDA : Everything begins and ends
at exactly the right time .
IRMA : Waiting a million years , just for us !
MIRANDA : Look ! Way up there in the sky !
MAM 'SELLE : Now I know !
MISS McCRAW : What do you know ?
MARION : A surprising number of human beings are without purpose
although it is probable
that they are performing some function unknown to themselves .
MIRANDA : Everything begins and ends
at exactly the right time and place .
( SCREAMING )
( WHISPERS ) Miranda .
Miranda !
( MUSIC BUILDS )
( HE MUMBLES )
( MUSIC FADES )
Jesus !
Coo-ee !
ECHO : Coo-ee !
( LOUD BUZZING )
( LOW , RHYTHMIC BOOMING )
( SCREAMING ECHO )
Let me have him now , son .
I 've had 30 years ' experience
puttin ' them in so they don 't fall out back on the road .
Eh , now lean back .
There . That 's it .
Take her quietly , Sergeant .
( LYRICAL MUSIC WITH PIANO MELODY )
( BIRDS CAWING )
( MUSIC FADES )
( WIND WHISTLING )
Oh , Jesus ! Jesus !
Help me !
( LYRICAL MUSIC WITH PIANO MELODY )
Mademoiselle , they found Irma .
What did you say ?
They found Irma , and she 's still alive .
Oh !
No one else ?
No .
Now go home .
There 's nothing you can do .
Go on , now . Go home !
This is a police matter .
Well , go on .
We 've got a bloody right to know . We 'd like to know what 's going on .
He 's right .
We simply want something done about it .
Where 's Bumpher ?
What we should do is go to the bloody rock ourselves .
We 've got our own self-respect to think about .
He 's right , there .
Get Bumpher out here . Come on .
Come out , Bumpher !
Let 's have another meeting .
Go back .
BUMPHER : Go on , go home .
The bloody lot of you .
Nothing you can do .
( MUSIC FADES )
We can thank the Lord for this merciful deliverance of our dear classmate , Irma
and pray that Marion and Miranda
and our beloved Miss McCraw will be likewise spared .
It has been seen fit
that Irma should convalesce at the home of Colonel Fitzhubert in Mount Macedon .
Although you 'll be delighted at these good tidings ,
I would ask you to remember , please ,
that of the three remaining lost members of the party , there is , as yet , no trace .
Would you come with me to my study , please , Miss Lumley ?
You may carry on , Mademoiselle .
( EXCITED CHATTING )
Wonderful news , Mrs Appleyard .
Don 't be so foolish , woman !
If all of them had been found but only one ?
This makes it worse . Far worse .
This tragedy is little more than a week old
and already three - three , mark you - sets of parents have written
advising me that their daughters will not be here next term .
Now the newspapers have something further to sensationalize about .
Newspapers all over the world have headlined our morbid affair , Miss Lumley .
I mean , you realise that , I suppose .
The three who have been withdrawn , plus the three still missing on the rock ...
Two , Mrs Appleyard , only two now . I 'm quite sure Irma will be coming back ...
That makes six , Miss Lumley ...
will not be with us next term .
In addition , there are several sets of tuition fees impossibly overdue .
Sara Waybourne , for instance .
Most inconsiderate , if I may say so , Mrs Appleyard .
Yes .
Well , I ...
I expect we shall see our way through somehow .
Don 't let me detain you , Miss Lumley . You have a class in a few minutes , I believe .
Senior needlework .
Just ask the Waybourne girl to come in to see me , please .
After luncheon will be convenient .
Yes , Mrs Appleyard .
Oh , and Miss Lumley .
Do your best to forbid any idle and morbid gossip about this whole wretched business .
Yes , Mrs Appleyard . I will .
( ♪ BEETHOVEN : " Adagio " from 5th Piano Concerto )
Who ? What ? Who is it ?
Shh !
Ah !
Remarkable . Hmm .
A week out in the bush and nothing more serious than shock and exposure .
Extraordinary !
No bones broken .
Some cuts and bruises to the face and hands .
To the hands especially .
Quite scratched .
The fingernails are all torn and broken .
There are several other unusual features .
Her head is quite badly bruised .
Probable concussion .
A blow , maybe ?
Or a fall ?
But then if she fell
why is the rest of the body unmarked ?
It 's quite unblemished .
And the feet , too , are quite unmarked , which is very strange
as she was not wearing shoes or stockings when she was found .
We found no trace of ' em up on the rock .
She 's quite intact .
I 'd give my head to know what really happened up there .
( MUSIC FADES )
What is it , my girl ?
Well , ma 'am , it 's Miss Irma .
Yes ?
Well , it 's about her clothing .
What is it , my dear ?
Well , I didn 't know whether the sergeant should be told .
There 's ... There 's no corset .
Miss Irma 's corset . It 's missing .
You did right , my dear . It can 't possibly be of any interest .
( TOM SINGS ) ♪ Tis my sorrow sorest
♪ Sad the falling forest
♪ The north wind brings me no rest ... ♪
( HE CONTINUES SINGING THE TUNE )
Any number of unsolved murders there are .
Take ... Take Jack the Ripper , for instance .
The police are up there again , naturally .
Thick as flies .
Someone reported seein ' a light flashing around a pigsty
on a place about a mile from the rock .
There 's some questions got answers and some haven 't .
No . There 'll be a solution turn up directly , more 'n likely .
A kidnappin ' .
Or , you know , something like that .
They might have fallen down a hole .
No , no . There 's a solution somewhere , all right .
There 's gotta be .
Come over here . Come on . Over here .
Did you know , lad , there are some plants that can move ?
No .
( LAUGHING )
Miss Lumley said you wanted to see me , Mrs Appleyard .
That is correct .
Come in .
( IMPATIENTLY ) Close the door , please .
I have written several letters to your guardian , Mr Cosgrove , Sara ,
but I have not been favoured with a reply thus far .
In fact , it is all of six months since I have received a letter
or a cheque .
I , therefore , have no alternative but to cancel all your extras .
This means that , as of today ,
you can no longer partake in dancing or drawing lessons .
And unless all your outstanding fees are paid by Easter ,
I 'm afraid we shall have to make other arrangements .
You know what that means , don 't you , Sara ?
You will have to go away .
There are places for girls in your predicament .
Institutions .
Now off you go .
Sara .
Sara ! What 's wrong with you ?
Are you feeling ill " ?
People don 't sit on cold steps in the dark unless they 're weak in the head .
You heard the bell . Go and wash for supper .
Aren 't you hungry ?
Then you 'd best go straight to bed .
Quickly .
Tell Mam 'selle I don 't want it . Thank you .
But you must eat . You 'll get sick if you don 't .
I 'm sick already . If I eat that , I 'll be even sicker .
Nonsense . Now come on , Miss Sara .
Do you know what , Minnie ?
No . What ?
I was in an orphanage once .
Were you , Sara ?
I had a brother then
called Bertie .
I told the matron I wanted to be a lady circus rider
on a white horse in a spangled dress .
She was afraid I 'd run away , so she shaved my head .
I bit her arm .
It bled .
So she painted my head with gentian violet .
( TOM SINGING QUIETLY )
♪ All through the forest
♪ The north wind brings me no rest
♪ And death is in the sky
♪ I love you , Minnie . ♪
I love you , darlin ' .
I feel sorry for them kids .
The ones on the rock , you mean ?
Yeah , them too .
I was thinkin ' of them other poor little devils ... here at the college .
Them . They 're all right .
Rollin ' in cash , most of them .
Or at least their mothers and fathers are .
Some of them are orphans .
Or wards or ...
You know .
( PANPIPE THEME )
Now I know .
What do you know ?
( WHISPER ) What do you know ?
I know that Miranda is a Botticelli angel .
( MUSIC FADES )
( CHATTING )
Hold it right there , thanks , gentlemen . That 's it .
Smile , please . Come on . Big smile .
Thank you , thank you .
Lindsay ! Lindsay ! Get those women over here , please .
Now they crossed the creek down there ?
( IN BACKGROUND ) The rope . Not that stuff . The other .
( IN BACKGROUND ) Give me that rope over here .
( IN BACKGROUND ) What about a cup of tea up here ?
Ah , tea .
Hello !
( CHATTING IN BACKGROUND )
- This is the local police . - Yes , yes .
Will you all gather over here , please ? All searchers over here .
All those not engaged , come over here , please .
Good , good .
As if looking up . Right up .
That 's it . Looking for a cave or something like that .
Little more expression in the face , sir .
( ♪ BEETHOVEN : " Adagio " from 5th Piano Concerto )
Hello , Irma .
Madame Fitzhubert showed me in .
How do you feel ?
Oh , Irma ! Oh , Irma .
We thought you had gone for ever .
Let me look at you , chérie .
You are so pale .
But prettier than ever .
Has the nephew paid you a visit yet ?
The one who found you ?
Yes .
And then the policeman .
And you couldn 't ...
I , I remember
nothing .
Nothing ! I remember nothing !
( MUSIC CONTINUES )
( WINGS FLAPPING )
( MUSIC FADES )
Albert !
Albert ?
Miss ?
You know who I am , don 't you ?
Yes , miss .
Well ...
What , miss ?
I 'd like to thank you .
For rescuing me .
On the rock .
It was nothin ' .
Besides , it weren 't me . It was Mr Michael .
He found you .
Though he don 't remember nothin ' .
Tell you the truth ...
I never give it another thought .
After the doc and the sarge put you in the stretcher .
Well ...
You know .
I suppose I 'd better be getting on with my job .
( PANPIPE MUSIC )
( MUSIC CONTINUES )
( DIALOGUE INAUDIBLE )
( MUSIC FADES )
( HE READS ALOUD SLOWLY )
- How are they ? - Better be cool .
Best place I know for keeping cold beer , the pond .
It 's hot up here .
Always is .
Right under the roof like this .
It 's a wonder you can get any sleep at all .
Been seeing a lot of that Miss Leopold lately , eh ?
Yes .
The summer will soon be over .
Just as well , probably .
Don 't think this punt will be safe enough to take out again .
It 's sad really .
Like someone dying .
I mean the summer .
The end of the summer is like ...
Miranda used to say
that everything begins
and ends
at exactly the right time and place .
Irma ...
What happened on the rock ?
I 'm going away .
Up north to Queensland .
- Michael ! - Irma ! Irma !
( ORGAN MUSIC PLAYS )
♪ Rock of ages , cleft for me
♪ Let me hide myself in thee
♪ Let the water and the blood
♪ From thy riven side which flowed
♪ Be of sin the double cure
♪ Cleanse me from this guilt and power
♪ While I draw this fleeting breath
♪ When my eyelids close in death
♪ When I soar through tracks unknown
♪ See thee on thy judgement throne
♪ Rock of ages , cleft for me
♪ Let me hide myself in thee
♪ Amen . ♪
( ORGAN PLAYING HYMN : " O Hear Us When We Cry to Thee " )
( CHATTING )
( MUSIC AND CHATTING STOP )
( DOG BARKS )
Morning .
Send that reporter packing .
Girls , girls , get inside at once !
( WHISPERS ) There you are , Miranda dear .
You like these best .
Mr Whitehead gave them to me , to give to you .
My dear ...
My sweet Miranda .
( SHE GASPS )
She likes daisies best of all .
Oh , Sara ! Oh , Sara !
You do know that Miranda might not come back .
Miranda knows lots of things other people don 't know .
Secrets .
She knew she wouldn 't come back .
( SHE PLAYS PIANO )
Fanny , you are ridiculously out of step .
Pay attention to the music , please !
( INSECTS CHIRPING )
Excuse me , Miss Lumley .
Voila , mes enfants ! See who we have with us today ?
Our dear Irma is with us but for a few hours .
She is leaving soon to join her parents in Europe .
Alors , mes enfants . For ten minutes , you may talk as you choose .
If you approve , Miss Lumley .
( INSECTS CHIRPING )
( SHE BEGINS TO PLAY )
- Tell us , Irma ! Tell us ! - Yes , Irma , tell us !
- Tell us , Irma ! Tell us ! - What happened to Miranda , Irma ?
- You know what happened . Tell us ! - Tell us , Irma !
( HYSTERICAL SCREAMING )
Tell us , Irma !
- Why won 't you tell us , Irma ? - You know where they are .
Just tell us , Irma , tell us .
They 're dead ! All dead and gone ! In a filthy damp cave full of bats .
They 're going rotten and you know where !
Edith , you are a liar and a fool !
( EDITH SCREAMS )
( GIRLS QUIETEN DOWN )
( EDITH CRYING )
Mam 'selle ?
It 's for her own good !
To cure her terrible stooping !
Mon dieu !
( CLOCK TICKING )
( KNOCK ON DOOR )
Come in .
Well ? Come in .
My notice , ma 'am .
( SHE GROANS )
Have we an invalid in the house ?
Miss Sara 's supper , ma 'am .
Mademoiselle asked me , seeing as the child 's feeling poorly .
Oh .
Minnie .
Hm ?
Kindly tell Miss Sara not to put her light out until I 've had a word with her .
Yes , ma 'am .
( WHISPERS ) This is not a charitable institution .
You recall our recent discussion , Sara .
Answer me when I address you , child .
Yes .
I have considered your situation most carefully ,
and I have searched my mind and my conscience for a solution .
But this is not a charitable institution .
And as your fees have not been forthcoming , I have ...
been forced to make certain arrangements on your behalf .
You will be returned to the orphanage .
( DOOR CLOSES )
( CLOCK TICKING )
( SOBBING )
God , help me !
( SOMBRE MUSIC )
( SHE SOBS )
( RUSTLING )
( DOOR CLOSES )
( CRASHING )
( SOMBRE MUSIC STOPS )
You still thinking about that bloody rock ?
I can 't help it .
It comes back at night in dreams .
I had a funny dream last night .
There was this smell . Real strong .
It was like ... like I was wide awake .
Dead quiet .
Pansies . That 's what it smelt like .
And the whole place was all lit up , bright as day .
Pitch black outside .
- And there she is . - Who ?
Who was it ?
It was only a bloody dream !
My kid sister .
Haven 't seen her since the orphanage .
She always liked pansies .
And she went ... all sort of ...
misty-like .
I calls out ,
" Sara , don 't go yet . "
" Goodbye , Bertie , " she says .
" I 've come a long way to see ya , and now I must go . "
And she went .
Clear through that wall over there .
Sit down , please , Mademoiselle .
Merci .
We were speaking last night about the Waybourne girl .
You expressed concern over the state of her health .
Yes , Madame .
We have been relieved of any further responsibility .
Her guardian , Mr Cosgrove , arrived this morning and took her away with him .
But ...
But was she fit enough to travel ?
Apparently .
I should have been here to supervise her packing .
I , myself , helped Sara put a few things she especially wanted
into her little covered basket .
Mr Cosgrove was in a hurry to get away .
I shall not be coming into luncheon , Mademoiselle .
Kindly tell them not to lay a place for me .
Nor for Sara ?
Nor for Sara .
Is that rouge I see on your cheek , Mademoiselle ?
Powder , Madame . I find it becoming .
( WHISPERS ) Oh , God !
( LIVELY CHATTER )
Thank you very much for the lovely breakfast !
Bye-bye ! Au revoir ! Bye-bye !
Hope you have a nice holiday !
Bye-bye ! Bye-bye ! Au revoir !
Au revoir , mes enfants .
♪ Frère Jacques , Frère Jacques Dormez vous ? Dormez vous ? ♪
Au revoir !
Arthur , my late husband , and I ,
always took our annual holidays in Bournemouth .
Mmm . It 's a delightful place .
Absolutely delightful .
Nothing changed . Ever .
For 40 years .
The pier , the sands and the people .
And that guest house .
So dependable .
Completely and utterly dependable .
- A little more , Mam 'selle ? - No , Madame .
As you wish .
( GLASS SMASHES )
I came to depend so much on Greta McCraw .
So much masculine intellect .
I came to rely on that woman . Trust her .
How could she allow herself to be spirited away ?
Lost .
Raped .
Murdered in cold blood like a silly schoolgirl on that ...
wretched Hanging Rock .
Will Sara Waybourne be coming back this term , Madame ?
Oh !
Now where was I ?
Oh , yes !
Bournemouth .
What a delightful place !
Nothing changed .
Ever .
Bloody kids !
( BUZZING )
Oh ! ( CRIES )
- ( WOMAN SCREAMING ) - ( KNOCKING )
( CLOCK TICKING )
Sara !
( TICKING STOPS )
The body of Mrs Arthur Appleyard , principal of Appleyard College ,
was found at the base of Hanging Rock on Friday 27th March , 1900 .
Although the exact circumstances of her death are not known ,
it is believed she fell while attempting to climb the rock .
A search for the missing schoolgirls and their governess
continued spasmodically for the next few years without success .
To this day , their disappearance remains a mystery .
( ♪ BEETHOVEN : " Adagio " from 5th Piano Concerto )